Jordan Cole

Full Stack Developer

Fort Thomas, KY 41075 jordancole1234@yahoo.com 8596093174

Experienced Software Engineer with history of developing complex and efficient code, identifying and repairing bugs, and creatively finding solutions. Skilled at forecasting timetables for the development and implementation of software and proficient at analyzing company/business requirements and planning software models accordingly.

Willing to relocate: Anywhere

Authorized to work in the US for any employer

Work Experience

Software Developer

Seven Hills Technology - Sharonville, OH June 2021 to Present

- Worked within an agile team and helped prioritize and scope feature requests to ensure that the biggest impact features were worked on first.
- Develop, test, and implement new software programs
- Work with experienced team members to conduct root cause analysis of issues, review new and existing code and/or perform unit testing
- Communicate effectively and professionally in all forms of communication with internal and external
- · Design and implemented an advanced messaging feature in iOS and Android
- Implement localization or globalization of software

Software Developer

Squerl Inc - Remote

February 2020 to Present

- Responsible for API design and development of RESTful Services for enterprise products in the business.
- Worked within an agile team and helped prioritize and scope feature requests to ensure that the biggest impact features were worked on first.
- Worked on building new React components for customer-facing web and mobile applications which improved page loading times
- Regulated software deployment by utilizing Amazon Web Services.
- Work with a software team to determine the best solutions for projects
- Create intuitive software that answers company needs and strategies
- · Collaborated with Senior Engineers to provide creative software solutions for movie industry
- Coordinated with UI/UX designers to enhance their website and mobile apps.

Senior Software Engineer (Contractor)

Chasecraft Mcs LLC - Remote September 2019 to November 2020

- Led team of 5 overseeing all aspects of development, increasing user base by 300%
- Built extensive server load balancer which reduced client connection time by 4 seconds
- Develop infrastructure of auto-scaling servers using cloud services
- Minimized costs of cloud services by improving auto scaling application
- Assemble technical design documents outlining technical aspects of software
- Collaborated with Managers to meet project requirements
- Worked with software team to determine best practices for projects
- Acted as point of contact for Managers when there were critical errors.

Education

High School Diploma

Highlands High School - Fort Thomas, KY August 2016 to May 2020

Links

https://github.com/jordancole18

https://gitlab.com/jordan2118

https://www.linkedin.com/in/jordan-avery-cole/

Certifications and Licenses

Apple Service Fundamentals

October 2019 to May 2020

The Apple Service Fundamentals Exam (SVC-19A) is a computer-based knowledge test that Pearson VUE offers online. Successful completion of this exam fulfills the prerequisite requirement for Apple Certified iOS Technician (ACiT) 2019 certification and Apple Certified Mac Technician (ACMT) 2019 certification.

Google Professional Certification | IT Automation with Python

March 2021 to Present

This is a Google Professional Certificate which covers Python Programming, IT Support, Google Cloud, Networking, System Administration and Automation

https://coursera.org/share/a0cc222025d2593a3de528d06fa8676e